## **Professional Summary**

Seasoned Technology Consultant with over 12 years of experience spanning technical and functional domains of SAP and project management. A track record of delivering integrated solutions meeting customers' expectations employing various techniques backed with vast knowledge to translate business needs into technical solutions.

# **Expertise**

Project Management Technical Lead
Requirement Analysis SAP Consulting

**Work Experience** 

**TechMahindra** Nov 2020 – Present **DXC Technology** Dec 2008 – Nov 2018

# Relevant project experience

Saudi Aramco Dhahran, Saudi Arabia 10/2021 to present

Project type: Custom Application

Role: Project Lead Responsibilities:

Lead the project to implement a portal solution that aims to automate
 IKTVA processes for business users, suppliers and auditors.

Saudi Aramco Dhahran, Saudi Arabia 11/2020 to 09/2021

Project type: SD and IS-Oil

Role: Project Lead Responsibilities:

> Lead the project planning and execution to introduce a centralized domestic customers data controls process with the required approval workflows and integration with existing standard and custom processes.

Almarai Riyadh, Saudi Arabia 11/2017 to 02/2018

Project type: Transportation Management

Role: On-site Technical Team Lead

Responsibilities:

- Setup of PPF to facilitate invoice, certificates and waybill generation for all client transport orders in SAP TM along with required enhancements.

Saudi Electricity Company Dammam, Saudi Arabia 11/2015 to 11/2017

Project type: IFRS and IFRS Support

Role: Technical Team Lead

Responsibilities:

- Evaluate available tools to identify effort required and gaps that need to be addressed for each of them.
- Enhance the client's FI/CO systems to allow reporting and processing based on both SOCPA (local GAAP) and IFRS (International Financial Reporting Standards) for areas such as leasing, overhead cost allocation etc.
- Switch the leading valuation to IFRS along with all required technical changes in the processes and procedures along with the introduction of a new ledger.

Saudi Electricity Company

Dammam, Saudi Arabia

11/2014 to 10/2015

Project type: E-Invoicing
Role: Technical Team Lead

## Responsibilities:

- Enhance PO and SES processes to accommodate client's E-Invoicing requirements during IR generation.
- Automation of credit memo generation based on business rules related to IRs and GRs.

Saudi Electricity Company

Dammam, Saudi Arabia

01/2015 to 05/2015

Project type: Work Clearance Management Implementation

Role: Technical Team Lead

#### Responsibilities:

- Enhance the standard SAP WCM system to meet the client's 5-Star committee standards of workplace safety in a seamless integration with PM processes.
- Planning, managing and tracking technical deliveries to ensure timely deliveries while sustaining quality standards.

Saudi Electricity Company

Dammam, Saudi Arabia

08/2014 to 05/2015

Project type: Restructuring (Single Buyer Entity)

Role: Technical Team Lead

## Responsibilities:

- Technical architecture of the solution to establish a financial entity in the client's SAP system acting as a Power Production Accounting entity.
- Create a detailed "Cost Sheet" that leverages FI, PS and PM data giving business visibility of organization wide cost allocations.

Saudi Electricity Company

Dammam, Saudi Arabia

01/2013 to 06/2014

Project type: Restructuring and Rollout

Role: Technical Team Lead

## Responsibilities:

- Technical input during bidding for resourcing, tools and timelines.
- Planning, managing and tracking technical deliveries to ensure timely deliveries while sustaining quality standards.

Saudi Electricity Company

Dammam, Saudi Arabia

09/2012 to 12/2012

Project type: Change Management

Role: Technical Consultant

Responsibilities:

- Assessment of client change requests including planning and technical recommendations.
- Technical Specifications, Design and Implementation of approved changes.

Saudi Electricity Company

Dammam, Saudi Arabia

11/2009 to 06/2012

Project type: Logistics Implementation

Role: Technical Consultant

Responsibilities:

- Leading a team of technical consultants responsible for data migration, using ETL processes in association with a specialized data migration vendor, of Logistics data from legacy systems to SAP ensuring reconciliation and quality.
- Technical and Functional support of MM, PM and PS implementations.

Saudi Arabian Airlines

Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

12/2008 to 09/2009

Project type: MRO Implementation

Role: Technical Consultant

Responsibilities:

Part of a team responsible for migrating HCM data from legacy systems to SAP
 ECC6 along with technical and functional support for HCM.

## **Education**

• BSc, Software Engineering, KFUPM, Dhahran, Eastern Region, Saudi Arabia

### References

Available upon request